<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">3D Lighting Controls Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">3-D Lighting Controls Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">3-D Lighting Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box helps control the appearance of the 3-D image of the model in the lower right corner of the Working Area. &#160;The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">3-D Lighting Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is displayed by selecting </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">View|3-D Lighting…</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> &#160;There are six controls in the dialog box. &#160;The three controls on the left set the position of the light. The other three set different aspects of the light intensity.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2"><text styleclass="Heading2" translate="true">Light Position</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The coordinate system for the light has its origin in the center of the screen. &#160;X increases to the right. &#160;Y increases toward the top of the screen. Z increases out from the screen toward the viewer. The units of the coordinate system are arbitrary. &#160;They merely control the direction of the light.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2"><text styleclass="Heading2" translate="true">Light Intensity</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The light is considered to have three components: Ambient light, Diffuse light and Specular light. &#160;Ambient light is light that does not come from any particular direction. &#160;For instance, light from the sky would be considered ambient light. &#160;Diffuse light comes from a particular direction but is reflected evenly off a surface. &#160;However, surfaces directed at the light will receive more light than those directed away from the light. Specular light, like diffuse light is directional. &#160;However, it causes a bright spot on the surface on which it is shining. </text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
